Irisviel.
アイリスフィール
Are you all right?
大丈夫ですか
So they waited for Kiritsugu to leave before attacking head-on...
切嗣の不在を狙って正面突破ってわけ
That lightning, and this brazen method of assault...
先ほどの雷鳴
それに憚ることを知らぬこの出方
The enemy is most likely Rider.
おそらく敵はライダーです
Utw
Presents
Kurikaesu sekai nando te wo nobashitara
繰り返す世界 何度手を伸ばしたら
How many times must I reach my hand out to this repeating world
Kurikaesu sekai nando te wo nobashitara
繰り返す世界 何度手を伸ばしたら
How many times must I reach my hand out to this repeating world
Hakanai namida wa kuroi kokoro tokasu no
儚い涙は黒い心溶かすの？
For the fleeting tears to soften my black heart?
Hakanai namida wa kuroi kokoro tokasu no
儚い涙は黒い心溶かすの？
For the fleeting tears to soften my black heart?
Mebaedashita omoi ga mune ni hibiita nara
芽生え出した思いが胸に響いたなら
If these awakened feelings resonated in my heart
Mebaedashita omoi ga mune ni hibiita nara
芽生え出した思いが胸に響いたなら
If these awakened feelings resonated in my heart
Kimi no tonari de zutto kawarazu mamoru darou
君の隣でずっと変わらず護るだろう
I'd stand guard beside you forever and ever
Kimi no tonari de zutto kawarazu mamoru darou
君の隣でずっと変わらず護るだろう
I'd stand guard beside you forever and ever
Ochita kibou wo hirotte
堕ちた希望を拾って
If I could pick up these fallen hopes
Ochita kibou wo hirotte
堕ちた希望を拾って
If I could pick up these fallen hopes
Asu ni tsunaide yukeba
明日に繋いでゆけば
And link them on to tomorrow
Asu ni tsunaide yukeba
明日に繋いでゆけば
And link them on to tomorrow
Karamatta ibitsu na negai datte hodokeru
絡まった歪な願いだってほどける
Even these entwined, twisted wishes will come apart
Karamatta ibitsu na negai datte hodokeru
絡まった歪な願いだってほどける
Even these entwined, twisted wishes will come apart
Hikari wo kazashite tamerai wo keshita
光をかざして躊躇いを消した
I've held up the light and erased my hesitation
Hikari wo kazashite tamerai wo keshita
光をかざして躊躇いを消した
I've held up the light and erased my hesitation
Agetakatta no wa mirai de
あげたかったのは未来で
What I wanted to give you is in the future
Agetakatta no wa mirai de
あげたかったのは未来で
What I wanted to give you is in the future
Naiteru yoru daita mama
泣いてる夜抱いたまま
Crying and embracing the night
Naiteru yoru daita mama
泣いてる夜抱いたまま
Crying and embracing the night
Nageki wo sakende
嘆きを叫んで
Screaming its grief out loud
Nageki wo sakende
嘆きを叫んで
Screaming its grief out loud
Fumiireta ashi wo tooku no risou ga
踏み入れた足を遠くの理想が
The distant ideals gently heal
Fumiireta ashi wo tooku no risou ga
踏み入れた足を遠くの理想が
The distant ideals gently heal
Sotto iyashite yuku
そっと癒してゆく
These legs that've stepped forward
Sotto iyashite yuku
そっと癒してゆく
These legs that've stepped forward
Tashika na kizuna wo tsuyoku nigirisusumou
確かな絆を強く握り進もう
I'll hold on tight to these definite bonds as I advance
Tashika na kizuna wo tsuyoku nigirisusumou
確かな絆を強く握り進もう
I'll hold on tight to these definite bonds as I advance
Dokomade mo
どこまでも
No matter where I go
Dokomade mo
どこまでも
No matter where I go
Kegarekitta kiseki wo se ni
穢れきった奇跡を背に
I'll shoulder these tainted miracles
Kegarekitta kiseki wo se ni
穢れきった奇跡を背に
I'll shoulder these tainted miracles
Whoa!
Hey, Saber!
いよう セイバー
Rider...
ライダー
I heard you guys have a castle, so I came over to see it...
城を構えていると聞いて来てみたが
But it's kind of gloomy-looking.
何ともしけた所だのう
And what's with that battle attire?
大体何だ のっけからその無粋な戦支度は
You aren't wearing your fashionable suit tonight?
今宵は当世風のファッションはしとらんのか
Rider, what did you come for?
ライダー 貴様 何をしに来た
Can't you tell?
見てわからんか
For a drink. What else?
一献交わしに来たに決まっておろうが
Come on, stop standing there and show me around.
ほれ そんな所に突っ立ってないで案内せい
Surely you have a garden fit for a banquet.
どこぞ宴に誂え向きの庭園でもないのか
I can't stand this castle. It's too dusty!
この荒れ城の中は埃っぽくてかなわん
The Grail is fated to end up in the
hands of the one most worthy of it.
聖杯は相応しき者の手に渡る定めにあるという
And the battle here in Fuyuki City will determine who that person is.
それを見定めるための儀式が
この冬木における闘争だというが
But if it's just a means to decide, then there's no need for bloodshed.
なにも見極めをつけるだけならば
血を流すには及ばない
If all the Heroic Spirits can acknowledge each other's ranks...
英霊同士 お互いの「格」に納得がいったなら
...then the matter will settle itself.
それで自ずと答えは出る
Oh?
So you wish to start by comparing your rank against mine, Rider?
それで まずは私と「格」を競おうというわけか ライダー
Indeed.
その通り
As we both call ourselves kings, this is not something we can avoid.
お互いに「王」を名乗って譲らぬとあれば捨て置けまい
You might consider this a Grail Dialogue rather than a Grail War.
いわばこれは「聖杯戦争」ならぬ「聖杯問答」
Which of us is more suited to be the king of the Grail?
どちらがより「聖杯の王」に相応しい器か
The matter will clarify itself as we drink.
酒杯に問えばつまびらかになるというものよ
That's more than enough nonsense...
戯れはそこまでにしておけ
...mongrel.
雑種
Archer, what is your business here?
アーチャー 何故ここに
Ah, I saw him in town, so I figured I might as well invite him.
いやな 街でこいつの姿を見かけたんで
誘うだけ誘っておいたのさ
You're late, Goldy.
遅かったではないか 金ピカ
Well, you did come here by foot, unlike me. Makes sense.
まあ 余と違って歩行なのだから無理もないか
So you chose to hold the Banquet of Kings in this depressing place?
よもやこんなうっとうしい場所を「王の宴」に選ぶとは
How will you make up for the rudeness of making me walk all the way here?
オレにわざわざ足を運ばせた非礼をどう詫びる
Aw, don't say that.
まあ 固いことを言うでない
Here, start with a drink.
ほれ 駆けつけ一杯
何だこの安酒は
What is this cheap swill?
You really thought we could discern a Heroic Spirit hierarchy with this?
こんなもので本当に英雄の格が量れるとでも思ったか
Is that so?
そうかあ この土地の市場で仕入れたうちじゃあ
This was among the best I could find at the city marketplace.
こいつはなかなかの逸品だぞ
That's because you are ignorant of true drink, foolish mongrel.
そう思うのは お前が本当の酒というものを知らぬからだ
雑種めが
Behold, and acknowledge your folly.
見るがいい そして思い知れ
This is the drink of a king.
これが「王の酒」というものだ
Splendid indeed.
これは重畳
This is really good!
美味い
My treasury houses only the finest,
whether it be drinks or weapons.
酒も剣も 我が宝物庫には至高の財しか有り得ない
This alone should indicate which among us is the greatest of kings.
これで王としての格付けは決まったようなものであろう
Archer.
アーチャーよ
Your finest drink is indeed worthy of the best vessel.
貴様の極上の酒はまさしく至宝の杯に相応しい
Unfortunately, the Grail is not a drinking cup.
が あいにく聖杯と酒器とは違う
First, you'll have to tell us the scale of the wish you have for the Grail.
まず貴様がどれほどの大望を聖杯に託すのか
それを聞かせてもらわねば始まらん
Quit making distinctions, mongrel.
仕切るな 雑種
The premise of having to fight for the Grail already makes no sense to begin with.
第一聖杯を「奪い合う」という前提からして理を外しているのだぞ
The Grail already belongs to me.
そもそもにおいて あれはオレの所有物だ
Every single one of the world's treasures trace their origin back to my treasury.
世界の宝物はひとつ残らず その起源を我が蔵に遡る
So you're saying you once had the Grail?
じゃあ貴様 昔聖杯を持っていたことがあるのか
You would know exactly what it is?
どんなもんか正体も知ってると
No.
知らぬ
Don't see this with your mongrel standards.
雑種の尺度で測るでない
The wealth in my treasury has long
since surpassed my own knowledge.
オレの財の総量はとうにオレの認識を越えている
But the fact that it's treasure is enough to make it mine.
だが「宝」であるという時点で 我が財であることは明白だ
And anyone who would take it for themselves...
それを勝手に持ち出そうなどと
...is nothing but a brazen thief.
盗人猛々しいにも程があるぞ
Your words are no different from Caster's insane rants.
おまえの言はキャスターの世迷い事とまったく変わらない
It appears he isn't the only Servant to have gone mad.
錯乱したサーヴァントは奴一人ではなかったらしい
Well, I don't know...
いやいや どうだかな
I think I have an idea what Goldy's real name is.
なんとなく この金ピカの真名に心当たりがあるぞ 余は
Then what, Archer?
じゃあ 何か アーチャー
Are you saying we just need your consent if we want the Grail?
聖杯が欲しければ貴様の承諾さえ得られれば良いと
Exactly.
然り だがお前ら如き雑種に
However, I have absolutely no reason to
bestow such a gift to mongrels like you both.
オレが褒賞を遣わす理由はどこにもない
Selfish, aren't you?
貴様 もしかしてケチか
Fool.
たわけ オレの恩情に与るべきはオレの臣下と民だけだ
Only my subjects and people are worthy of my compassion.
In other words, Rider, if you submit yourself to me...
故にライダー お前がオレの許に下るというなら
I can let you have a drinking cup or two anytime.
杯のひとつやふたつ いつでも下賜してやって良い
That's out of the question.
そりゃ出来ん相談だわなあ
But, Archer, it's not like you actually want the Grail, do you?
でもなあ アーチャー
貴様 べつだん聖杯が惜しいってわけでもないんだろう
Of course not.
無論だ
But I must administer my judgment
to thieves who are after my treasures.
だがオレの財を狙う賊には然るべき裁きを下さねばならぬ
It's a matter of principle.
要は筋道の問題だ
So then, Archer...
つまり何なんだ アーチャー
What justice and reasoning do you speak of?
そこにはどんな義があり どんな道理があると
Of the law.
法だ
My law that I set down as king.
オレが王として敷いた オレの法だ
Perfect, indeed.
完壁だな 自らの法を貫いてこそ 王
You're the king because you see your own law through.
But you know...
だがな 余は聖杯が欲しくて仕方がないんだよ
I want the Grail so much that I can't stop myself.
It's my style to simply take what I want.
で 欲した以上は略奪するのが余の流儀だ
After all, I'm Iskandar...
なにせこのイスカンダルは征服王であるが故
...King of Conquerors.
It doesn't matter.
是非もあるまい お前が犯し オレが裁く
You break the law, and I punish you.
There is no room for discussion.
問答の余地などどこにもない
Which means...
そうなると
...all that's left for us is to cross swords.
後は剣を交えるのみ
Anyway, Archer.
が アーチャーよ ともかくこの酒は飲みきってしまわんか
Why don't we finish drinking this wine?
We can fight each other to the death afterwards.
殺し合うだけなら後でもできる
But of course.
当然だ それとも貴様
Or do you think light of this wine that I let you have?
まさか オレの振る舞った酒を蔑ろにする気でいたのか
Absolutely not!
冗談ではない これだけの美酒を捨て置けるものか
How could I not help myself to such delicious wine?
King of Conquerors.
征服王よ
You acknowledge someone else's rightful
ownership of the Grail, yet you'll take it by force?
お前は聖杯の正しい所有権が他人にあるものと認めた上で
なおかつそれを力で奪うのか
Why would you go so far for the Grail?
そうまでして 聖杯に何を求める
True incarnation.
受肉だ
Huh?
Huh?!
はあ オマエ 望みは世界征服だったんじゃぎゃわ
Hey, wasn't your goal supposed to be world conquest-
Idiot.
馬鹿者
What's the point in having some
drinking cup conquer the world for me?
たかが杯なんぞに世界を獲らせてどうする
Conquest is a dream I'll entrust to myself.
征服は己自身に託す夢
All I want from the Grail...
聖杯に託すのは あくまでもそのための第一歩だ
...is the first step of that process.
Mongrel.
雑種 よもやそのような瑣事のために このオレに挑むのか
You'd challenge me for something so small?
Even if mana gives us form in this world, we still ultimately remain Servants.
いくら魔力で現界してるとはいえ 所詮我らはサーヴァント
I want to be firmly rooted to this world as a living human.
余は転生したこの世界に
一個の命として根を下ろしたい
And with a body of my very own, I shall defy both heaven and earth.
身体一つの我を張って 天と地に向かい合う
That's what the act of conquest is all about.
それが征服という「行い」の総て
It's how it begins, proceeds, and is finished.
そのように開始し 押し進め
成し遂げてこその
Such is my path of conquest.
我が覇道なのだ
I've decided, Rider.
決めたぞ ライダー
I shall kill you myself.
貴様はこのオレが手ずから殺す
There's no need to point that out now.
今さら念を押すこともなかろうて
I also intend to take that treasury of
yours for myself, so be ready for that.
余もな 貴様の宝物庫とやらを奪い尽くす気でおるから覚悟しておけ
That's not how a king should be.
そんなものは 王の在り方ではない
Let us hear what you wish for, then.
では 貴様の懐の内 聞かせてもらおうか
I wish for my homeland's salvation.
私は 我が故郷の救済を願う
With the omnipotent wish-granting device,
万能の願望機をもってして
I shall avert Britain's fate of destruction.
ブリテンの滅びの運命を変える
They're drinking, of all things.
よりにもよって 酒盛りとはな
Is it really okay to just leave Archer alone?
アーチャーをこのまま放置しておいても宜しいので
I can't do anything.
仕方あるまい
Since he's the king among kings, he can't
possibly ignore the dialogue being thrust at him.
王の中の王にあらせられては
突きつけられた問答に背を向けるわけにもいかんだろうからな
By the way, Kirei.
ところで 綺礼
What do you think of the difference
in strength between Rider and Archer?
ライダーとアーチャーの戦力差 君はどう考える
I think the key lies in whether Rider has a
trump card more powerful than Gordius Wheel.
ライダーに「神威の車輪」を上回るような切り札があるのか否か
そこに尽きると思われますが
Since Rider is enjoying his drink with his Master undefended, there is no better time than now for a surprise attack.
ライダーが マスターともども無防備に酒盛りに興じている今は
またとない襲撃の好機
It doesn't matter if we have a chance of winning or not.
この際 勝算があるかどうかは問題ではない
Even if Assassin is defeated, we'll have achieved
our goal if we can discern the difference in strength.
たとえアサシンが敗退しても
彼我の戦力差を量ることができれば 目的は達成される
There's something we can probably try at this point, Kirei.
このあたりで一つ 仕掛けてみる手もあるかもな 綺礼
I have no objections.
異存はありません
It'll probably take about ten minutes to gather all the Assassins.
すべてのアサシンを呼び寄せるのに 十分ほどかかるかと
良し 号令を発したまえ
Good. Give the order.
Although this is a big gamble, we luckily have nothing to lose.
大博打ではあるが 幸いにして我々が失うものは何もない
Kirei, use a Command Spell to give this order to Assassin:
綺礼 令呪をもってアサシンへ命じよ
Achieve victory, no matter the cost.
犠牲を厭わず 勝利せよ とな
Hey, King of Knights.
なあ 騎士王
貴様今 「運命を変える」と言ったか
Did you just say that you would change fate?
Does that mean you wish to change the past?
それは過去の歴史を覆すということか
そうだ
That's right.
Even if it is a wish that a miracle cannot fulfill, if the Holy Grail truly is omnipotent, I'm sure...
たとえ奇跡をもってしても叶わぬ願いであろうと
聖杯が真に万能であるならば
必ずや
Uh, Saber...
ええと セイバー
Just making sure, but that Britain country fell during your time, during your rule, no?
確かめておくが
そのブリテンとかいう国が滅んだというのは
貴様の時代の話であろう 貴様の治世であったのだろう
That's right.
そうだ だからこそ私は許せない
That's why I can't accept it.
That's why I lament it.
だからこそ悔やむのだ あの結末を変えたいのだ
I want to change how it all ended.
Because it's none other than my responsibility...
他でもない 私の責であるが故に
Archer, what's so funny?
アーチャー 何がおかしい
自ら王を名乗り 皆から王と讃えられて
She calls herself a king and is praised by everyone as such...
Yet she says that she "laments" it?
そんな輩が「悔やむ」だと
How can I possibly keep a straight face?!
これが笑わずにいられるか
Saber.
セイバー 貴様よりにもよって
Surely you aren't saying that you spurn the very marks you left on history?
自らが歴史に刻んだ行いを否定するというのか
I am!
そうとも なぜ訝る なぜ笑う
Why are you puzzled?
Why do you laugh?
The country that gave me my blade, the
country I offered my life to, was destroyed.
剣を預かり 身命を捧げた故国が滅んだのだ
Why is it strange that I'd lament that?
それを悼むのがどうして可笑しい
Did you hear that, Rider?
おいおい聞いたか ライダー
The things this little girl who calls herself King of Knights is saying?!
この騎士王と名乗る小娘は
よりにもよって「故国に身命を捧げた」のだとさ
"The country I offered my life to", she says!
How is that funny at all?!
笑われる筋合いがどこにある
王たる者ならば身を挺して治める国の繁栄を願うはず
A king should make any sacrifice to ensure his country's prosperity.
No.
いいや違う
王が捧げるのではない
The king does not sacrifice anything.
国が 民草が その身命を王に捧げるのだ
It is the country and the people that sacrifice themselves for the king.
Absolutely not the other way round.
断じてその逆ではない
何を
What?
Those are the words of a tyrant!
それは暴君の治世ではないか
然り
Exactly.
We are heroes because we are tyrants.
我らは暴君であるが故に英雄だ
だがなセイバー
However, Saber.
If a king regrets his rule or its conclusion, that king is nothing but a fool.
自らの治世を その結末を悔やむ王がいるとしたら
それはただの暗君だ
暴君よりなお始末が悪い
Worse than a tyrant.
Iskandar, your reign ended with your heirs slain, and your empire dissolved into three parts.
イスカンダル
貴様とて 世継ぎを葬られ
築き上げた帝国は三つに引き裂かれて終わったはずだ
You have no regrets about how it ended?
その結末に
貴様は 何の悔いもないというのか
None.
ない
If the end was brought about by my decisions and the way my subjects lived, then I will accept its destruction as inevitable.
余の決断
余に付き従った臣下たちの生き様の果てに辿り着いた結末であるならば
その滅びは必定だ
悼みもしよう
I shall grieve. And I shall weep.
涙も流そう
But I shall never regret.
だが決して悔やみはしない
You...
そんな
ましてそれを覆すなど
Let alone undo it!
Such a foolish act would only mock all
who fought with me to build my empire!
そんな愚行は
余とともに時代を築いた全ての人間に対する侮辱である
Only brute warriors find glory in destruction!
滅びの華を誉れとするのは武人だけだ
Of what worth is a king who fails to protect the powerless?
力なき者を守らずしてどうする
A just rule, with just laws...
正しき統制 正しき治世 それこそが王の本懐だろう
Those are the true duties of a king!
So you, the king, are a slave to what is just?
で 王たる貴様は「正しさ」の奴隷か
I don't mind.
それでいい
A king would willingly die for his ideals.
理想に殉じてこそ王だ
そんな生き方は人ではない
That's not how a person should live.
If I rule a country as its king, I cannot hope to live as a person.
王として国を治めるのなら
人の生き方など望めない
King of Conquerors.
征服王
You could never understand, as you seek the Grail merely for your own benefit.
たかだか我が身の可愛さのあまりに
聖杯を求めるという貴様には解るまい
飽くなき欲望を満たすためだけに覇王となった貴様には
You, who became a ruler only to satisfy your endless greed!
無欲な王なぞ飾り物にも劣るわい
A king without greed is even worse than a figurehead!
Saber.
セイバーよ
You said you would die for your ideals.
「理想に殉じる」と貴様は言ったな
In life, you must have been a pure and honest saint.
なるほど 往年の貴様は清廉にして潔白な聖者であったことだろう
A noble and inviolable figure, certainly.
さぞや高貴で侵しがたい姿であったことだろう
だがな 殉教などという茨の道に
But who on Earth admires the martyr's thorny path?
いったい誰が憧れる
Who dreams of such a life?
焦がれるほどの夢を見る
王とはな
You see...
A king must be greedier, laugh louder,
and be more furious than everyone else.
誰よりも強欲に 誰よりも豪笑し 誰よりも激怒する
He must exemplify the extreme of all things, including good and evil.
清濁含めて人の臨界を極めたるもの
That is exactly why his subjects envy and adore him.
そう在るからこそ臣下は王を羨望し
王に魅せられる
And why the flame of wanting to be like the king can burn in the hearts of every civilian.
一人一人の民草の心に
「我もまた王たらん」と憧憬の火が灯る
騎士道の誉れたる王よ
Proud King of Knights.
The righteousness and ideals you bore may have saved your country once.
たしかに貴様が掲げた正義と理想は
ひとたび国を救い 臣民を救済したやも知れぬ
However...
だがな ただ救われただけの連中がどういう末路を辿ったか
I'm sure you know what happened to
those who were constantly and only saved.
それを知らぬ貴様ではあるまい
What?
何だと
You saved your subjects, but you never led them.
貴様は臣下を救うばかりで
導くことをしなかった
You never showed them what a king should be.
「王の欲」の形を示すこともなく
You abandoned your men when they lost their way.
道を見失った臣下を捨て置き
Alone and untroubled,
ただ独りで澄まし顔のまま
you followed your own pretty little ideals.
小綺麗な理想とやらを想い焦がれていただけよ
Thus, you are no true king.
故に貴様は生粋の「王」ではない
You are but a little girl, bound by the false idol of a king who serves others but not himself.
己のためではなく
人のための「王」という偶像に縛られていただけの
小娘にすぎん
I...
私は
What are you laughing at, Archer?
何を笑う アーチャー
Well, it's just that your anguished face was quite the sight to behold.
いや なに
苦悩するお前の顔が見物だったというだけさ
まるで褥で花を散らされる処女のような顔だった
It's just like the face of a virgin deflowered in bed.
Exactly what I like.
実にオレ好みだ
Bastard...!
貴様
アサシン
Assassin...
Is this your doing, Goldy?
これは貴様の計らいか 金ピカ
時臣め ゲスなまねを
Tokiomi humiliates himself.
無茶苦茶だ
This is ridiculous!
何でアサシンばっかり 次から次へと
Why are there so many Assassins?!
We are one, split into many.
我らは分断された個
A Servant who is many and also one.
群にして個のサーヴァント
Yet we are one with many shadows.
されど個にして群の
影
A Servant with multiple personalities
materializing into separate entities for each?
多重人格の英霊が
自我の数だけ実体化しているのか
R-Rider, uh...
ラ ライダー なあ おい
こらこら坊主 そう狼狽えるでない
Come on, boy. Calm yourself.
Regardless of whether you treat them as guests, they can still judge who is the greatest king.
宴の客を遇する度量でも
王の器は問われるのだぞ
You'll invite them to the banquet as well, King of Conquerors?
あんな奴儕までも宴に迎え入れるのか 征服王
Of course.
当然だ
The king's words are for all to hear.
王の言葉は万民に向けて発するもの
If they have come to listen, it doesn't matter if they are friend or foe.
わざわざ傾聴しに来た者ならば
敵も味方もありはせぬ
さあ 遠慮はいらぬ
Now, don't hold back!
Those who'd speak with us, come forth and take a cup.
共に語ろうという者はここに来て杯を取れ
This drink is as your blood!
この酒は貴様らの血と共にある
Very well.
なるほど
I did say this drink is as your blood.
この酒は貴様らの血と言ったはず
If you insist on spilling it...
敢えてブチ撒けたいというならば
So be it.
是非もない
Saber! Archer!
セイバー そしてアーチャーよ
これが宴の最後の問いだ
Here is our banquet's final question.
Must the king be alone in his superiority?
そも 王とは孤高なるや否や
王ならば 孤高であるしか…ない
The king has no choice but to be alone!
No, you don't understand at all.
ダメだな まったくもって分かっておらん
そんな貴様らには 余が今ここで
Looks like I'll have to show you exactly what a real king is.
真の王たる者の姿を見せつけてやらねばなるまいて
This is...
これは
固有結界ですって
A Reality Marble?!
Ridiculous...
そんな馬鹿な
心象風景の具現化だなんて
Turning one's imagined terra into reality...
Here, my armies once rode across the land.
ここはかつて我が軍勢が駆け抜けた大地
余と苦楽を共にした勇者たちが
A scenery every single one of my heroes who
shared in my joys and sorrows will never forget.
等しく心に焼き付けた景色だ
この世界 この景観を形にできるのは
I can make this world real because it
still exists within the hearts of all of us!
これが我ら全員の心象であるからさ
Behold my peerless army!
見よ 我が無双の軍勢を
Their bodies have been destroyed, and their souls have been offered to the world as Heroic Spirits.
肉体は滅び
その魂は英霊として世界に召し上げられて
Yet, these legendary heroes remain loyal to me!
それでもなお余に忠義する伝説の勇者たち
My bond with them is my greatest treasure, my path of kingship!
彼らとの絆こそ我が至宝 我が王道
イスカンダルたる余が誇る最強宝具
The ultimate Noble Phantasm that I, Iskandar, possess:
Ionian Hetairoi!
「王の軍勢」なり
Every single one of them is a Servant!
こいつら 一騎一騎がサーヴァントだ
久しいな 相棒
It's been a long time, partner.
A king must live a life more vivid than
any other and be a figure for all to admire!
王とは
誰よりも鮮烈に生き
諸人を魅せる姿を指す言葉
Yes!
然り 然り 然り
すべての勇者の羨望を束ね
The king is the one who collects the envy
of all his heroes and stands as their guide!
その道標として立つ者こそが王
Therefore, the king is not alone.
故に
王とは孤高にあらず
For his will equals that of all his followers combined!
その偉志は すべての臣民の志の総算たるが故に
Yes!
然り 然り 然り
Now, then...
さて では始めるか アサシンよ
Shall we begin, Assassin?
見ての通り 我らが具象化した戦場は平野
As you can see, the battlefield we've created is an open plain.
I'm afraid we hold the advantage with our superior numbers.
あいにくだが 数で勝るこちらに地の利はあるぞ
Annihilate them!
蹂躙せよ
That ending was disappointing.
幕切れは興醒めだったな
We've said all there is to say.
お互い言いたいことも言い尽くしたよな
I suppose that'll do for today.
今宵はこの辺でお開きとしようか
Wait, Rider.
待てライダー 私はまだ
I'm not done yet...
貴様はもう黙っとけ
You can keep your mouth shut.
Kings were to converse in tonight's banquet.
今宵は王が語らう宴であった
But I no longer recognize you as a king, Saber.
だがセイバー
余はもう貴様を王とは認めぬ
Little girl, wake up from that sad dream of yours.
なあ 小娘よ
いい加減にその痛ましき夢から醒めろ
If you don't, you'll someday lose even that
modicum of pride you have as a Heroic Spirit.
さもなくば貴様は
いずれ英雄としての最低限の誇りさえも失う羽目になる
The dream of the kingship you spoke of is a curse.
貴様の語る「王」という夢は
いわばそういう類の呪いだ
何だと
What?!
耳を傾ける必要はないぞ セイバー
You needn't listen to him, Saber.
お前は正しい
You are correct.
Follow the path you believe in.
己が信じる道を行くが良い
The agony and conflict you wallow in as you bear
the burden of a kingship too heavy for anyone...
人の身に余る王道を背負い込み
苦しみに足掻くその苦悩 その葛藤
慰みものとしてはなかなかに上等だ
It's really quite pleasurable to see.
せいぜい励めよ 騎士王とやら
Keep at it, King of Knights.
You might actually prove worthy of even more of my love.
ことによるとお前は
さらなる我が寵愛に値するかもな
Saber...
セイバー
思い出したのです
I remember.
「アーサー王は人の気持ちが分からない」と言い残して
There was once a knight who left Camelot, claiming that King Arthur didn't understand how others felt.
かつてキャメロットを去った騎士がいたことを
もしかしたら
Maybe...
...those sentiments were shared by everyone at the Round Table.
あれは円卓に集まった騎士たちの
誰もが抱いていた言葉なのかもしれません
Episode 11
Grail Dialogue
Shizuka ni utsuriyuku
Amidst the quietly shifting
静かに移りゆく
Shizuka ni utsuriyuku
Amidst the quietly shifting
静かに移りゆく
Tooi kioku no naka
Distant memories
遠い記憶の中
Tooi kioku no naka
Distant memories
遠い記憶の中
Omoide ni yorisoinagara
If I can find peace in my recollections
思い出に寄り添いながら
Omoide ni yorisoinagara
If I can find peace in my recollections
思い出に寄り添いながら
Kimi wo omoeru nara
While reminiscing about you
君を想えるなら
Kimi wo omoeru nara
While reminiscing about you
君を想えるなら
Itsumo minareteru madobe ni utsutta
I am all too familiar with the window reflection
いつも見慣れてる窓辺に映った
Itsumo minareteru madobe ni utsutta
I am all too familiar with the window reflection
いつも見慣れてる窓辺に映った
Sono hitomi wa ashita wo muite ita
Of your eyes that were gazing into the future
その瞳は明日を向いていた
Sono hitomi wa ashita wo muite ita
Of your eyes that were gazing into the future
その瞳は明日を向いていた
Ah sakaraenu sadame to shitte mo
Ah, even though I know there's no escaping this fate
あぁ 逆らえぬ運命と知っても
Ah sakaraenu sadame to shitte mo
Ah, even though I know there's no escaping this fate
あぁ 逆らえぬ運命と知っても
Kowakunai kokoro kara shinjite iru
I'm not afraid. I have faith from the bottom of my heart
怖くない 心から信じている
Kowakunai kokoro kara shinjite iru
I'm not afraid. I have faith from the bottom of my heart
怖くない 心から信じている
Shizuka ni utsuriyuku
Amidst the quietly shifting
静かに移りゆく
Shizuka ni utsuriyuku
Amidst the quietly shifting
静かに移りゆく
Tooi kioku no naka
Distant memories
遠い記憶の中
Tooi kioku no naka
Distant memories
遠い記憶の中
Kimi to sugoshita akashi wa
Proof of the time I spent with you
君と過ごした証は
Kimi to sugoshita akashi wa
Proof of the time I spent with you
君と過ごした証は
Tashika ni koko ni aru
Is right here with me
確かにここにある
Tashika ni koko ni aru
Is right here with me
確かにここにある
Afuredasu kimochi wo
You've shown me what it means
溢れ出す気持ちを
Afuredasu kimochi wo
You've shown me what it means
溢れ出す気持ちを
Oshiete kureta kara
To have overflowing feelings
教えてくれたから
Oshiete kureta kara
To have overflowing feelings
教えてくれたから
Kono sekai ga nakunatte mo
Even if this world were to end
この世界がなくなっても
Kono sekai ga nakunatte mo
Even if this world were to end
この世界がなくなっても
Watashi wa soko ni iru
I'll be right by your side
私はそこにいる
Watashi wa soko ni iru
I'll be right by your side
私はそこにいる
This begins the second stage.
ここから先は第二局目だ
私は普通の人間ではなくてよ
I'm not a normal human.
そんな簡単に済ませていい話ではないでしょう
It can't be that simple!
求めるところを為すがいい
Do as you desire.
Your path is now clear.
道は示されているぞ
だがそれは罰せられるべき悪徳だ
But that is an evil that must be punished!
Next Episode
The Grail's Invitation